Guide to the Ray Lyman Wilbur Personal Papers SC0064B
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Personal papers, Bulk, 1875-1949 1829-1949; bulk; Series 1
  - Foreign Students, Committee on Friendly Relations Among (Box 25)
  - Fort, Franklin W. (Box 25)
  - Fortune (Box 25)
  - Forum, The (Box 25)
  - Fosdick, Harry Emerson (Box 25)
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. (Box 25)
  - Foster, William T. (Box 25)
  - Fowler, Frederick Hall (& Mrs.) (Box 25)
  - Fowler, W. H. Begbie (Box 25)
  - France (Box 25)
  - France (misc.) (Box 25)
  - Frank, Glenn (& Mrs.) (Box 25)
  - Frankenfield, Budd (Box 25)
  - Frankel, Hermann (Box 25)
  - Franklin, Edward Curtis (Box 25)
  - Frantz, Harry Warner (Box 25)
  - Free, Arthur H. (Box 25)
  - Freeman, Miller (Box 25)
  - Frost, Howard (Box 25)
  - Fuller, William Parmer, Jr. (& Mrs.) (Box 25)
  - Furlong, Col. Charles Wellington (Box 25)
  - Gaiger, Dr. Philippe (Box 26)
  - Galpin, Perrin C. (Box 26)
  - Gardiner, Gertrude M. (Box 26)
  - Gardner, Dr. David Charles (Box 26)
  - Garfias, Valentine Richard (Box 26)
  - Garfield, Harry Augustus (Box 26)
  - Garner, John N. (Box 26)
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs (Box 26)
  - General Education Bard (Box 26)
  - General Quotations (Box 26)
  - Genealogical Foundation (Box 26)
  - George Washington University (Box 26)
  - Germany - Consuls General, etc. (Box 26)
  - German Relief (Box 26)
  - Gibson, Hugh (Box 26)
  - Glen, Marion (Box 26)
  - Glover, Katherine (Box 26)
  - Goethe, C. M. (Box 26)
  - Golden Gate Bridge (Box 26)
  - Golden Gate International Exposition, 1936-1937 (Box 26)
  - Golden Gate International Exposition, 1938 (Box 27)
  - Golden Gate International Exposition, 1939 (Box 27)
  - Golden Gate International Exposition, 1939, Jul-Dec (Box 27)
  - Golden Gate International Exposition, 1940-1941, 1946 Pacific House (Box 28)
  - Golder, Dr. Frank A. (Box 28)
  - Good, Carter V. (Box 28)
  - Good, James W. (Secretary of War) (Box 28)
  - Good Neighbor League, Inc. (Box 28)
  - Gordon, Boris B (Box 28)
  - Goucher College (Box 28)
  - Grant, Joseph Donohoe (Box 28)
  - Gray, Carl F (Box 28)
  - Greece (misc.) & Greeks (Box 28)
  - Green, A. Crawford (Box 28)
  - Greene, Jerome D. (Box 28)
  - Greenman, Mrs. Nellie (Box 28)
  - Greenslade, Vice Admiral John W. (Box 28)
  - Gregory, Thomas T. C. (Box 28)
  - Gregory, Warren (Box 28)
  - Griffin, (Robert) Allen (Box 28)
  - Griffithe, Farnham P. (Box 28)
  - Gros, Robert R. (Box 28)
  - Guerard, Prof. Albert Leon (Box 28)
  - Guerrier, Edith (Box 28)
  - Gunst, Morgan A. (& Mrs.) (Box 28)
  - Hager, A. E. (?) (Box 29)
  - Haight, Burl (Box 29)
  - Hallowell, John W. (Box 29)
  - Halsted, Sam T. (Box 29)
  - Hammond, Harry (Box 29)
  - Hammond, John Hays (Box 29)
  - Hammond, Mrs. Nellie B. (Box 29)
  - Hanna, Paul Robert (Box 29)
  - Hanvey, Howard G. (Box 29)
  - Hard, William (Box 29)
  - Harden, Barbara & Jane Ann (Box 29)
  - Harding, Warren G. (Box 29)
  - Harlow, Rex Francis (Box 29)
  - Harriman, Raymond Davis (Box 29)
  - Harvard University (Box 29)
  - Hastings, Senator Daniel 0 (Box 29)
  - Hastings, George Aubrey (Box 29)
  - Hatfield, George I. (Box 30)
  - Haverford College (Box 30)
  - Hawaii, Statehood for (Box 30)
  - Hawaii, University of & Territory of (Box 30)
  - Haynes, Jack E. (Box 30)
  - Hays, Alice Newman (Box 30)
  - Hays, Howard & son, Daniel M. (Box 30)
  - Hearst, William R. & family (Box 30)
  - Heath, Harold (&. Mrs.) (Box 30)
  - Heffner, Hubert Grouse (& Mrs.) (Box 30)
  - Hendrix College (Box 30)
  - Herman, Raphael (Box 30)
  - Herre, Dr. Albert W. C. T. (Box 30)
  - Herrold, George H. (Box 30)
  - Heatherington, Clark Wilson (Box 30)
  - Hibbon, John Grier (Box 30)
  - Hibberd, Isaac N. (Box 30)
  - Hicks, Clarence J. (Box 30)
  - Higley, Brodie G. (Box 30)
  - Hill, Charles Wentworth (Box 30)
  - Hill, Frank Ernest (Box 30)
  - Hillcrest Club (Box 30)
  - Hilton, Ronald (Box 30)
  - Hinsdale, Lester J. (Box 30)
  - Hinshaw, David (Box 30)
  - Hinton, W. J. (Box 30)
  - Hirst, Francis W. A. (Box 30)
  - Hoag, Dr. Ernest Bryant (Box 30)
  - Hobday, Robert D. (Box 30)
  - Hodges, Mr. & Mrs. Charles (sons: Lauder & Charles) (Box 30)
  - Hodgson, Caspar W. (of World Book Company) (Box 30)
  - Hoge, Mrs. Marcia (Box 30)
  - Holden, Paul Eugene (& Sally) (Box 30)
  - Holland, Ernest (Box 30)
  - Hollingsworth, Mr. & Mrs. James E. (Box 30)
  - Holsti, Dr. Rudolph (Box 30)
  - Hoover, Allen Henry (Box 30)
  - Hoover, Mrs. Herbert (Lou Henry) (Box 30)
  - Hoover, Herbert, Jr. (& family) (Box 30)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1894-1920 (Box 31)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1921-1927 (Box 31)
  - Hoover, Herbert: includes some 1920 campaign materials) (Box 31)
  - Hoover, Herbert: includes Hoover War Library, 1921-1929 (Box 32)
  - Hoover, Herbert, includes 1928 campaign materials (Box 32)
  - Hoover, Herbert, includes 1928 campaign materials (Box 32)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1929 (Box 32)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1930, 1931 (Box 33)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1932 (Box 33)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1933 (Box 33)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1934 (Box 33)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1935 (Box 34)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1936 (Box 34)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1936 (Box 34)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1937 (Box 34)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1938 (Box 34)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1939, 1940 (Box 35)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1941, 1942 (Box 35)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1943, 1944 (Box 35)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1945 (Box 35)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1946, 1947 (Box 35)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1948, 1949 (Box 36)
  - Hoover, Herbert: includes Addresses & Public Statements (Box 36)
  - Hoover, Herbert: includes American Relief Adm. (& Children's Fund) (Box 36)
  - Hoover, Herbert: includes Gifts to Stanford University (Box 36)
  - Hoover, Herbert: includes Nobel Prize for (Box 36)
  - Hoover, Theodore Jesse (Box 36)
  - Hope, Walter Ewing (Box 36)
  - Hopkins, Timothy (Box 36)
  - Hopkins, Mrs. Timothy (May & Lydia) (Box 36)
  - Hopwood, John Aldine (Box 36)
  - Hotchkiss, Willard Eugene (Box 36)
  - House, Irwin L. (Box 36)
  - Houston, David Franklin (Box 36)
  - Howard, Graeme Keith (Box 36)
  - Howard, Lowry S. (Box 36)
  - Howard University (Box 36)
  - Howell, John (Box 36)
  - Hughes, Charles Evans (Box 36)
  - Hull, Cordell (Box 36)
  - Hurley, Patrick J. (Box 36)
  - Hu-Shih, Dr. (Box 36)
  - Hutchins, President Robert M. (University of Chicago) (Box 36)
  - Hyde, Arthur M. (Box 36)
  - Ichihashi, Prof. Yamato (Box 37)
  - Ickes, Harold L. (Secretary. of Interior) (Box 37)
  - Illinois, University of (Box 37)
  - Immigration - misc. (Box 37)
  - Immigration, National Committee for Constructive Legislation (Box 37)
  - Indiana University (Box 37)
  - Indians, American (Box 37)
  - Industrial Relations, Progress, etc. (Box 37)
  - Institute of International Education (Box 37)
  - Institute of International Relations & Council on (Box 37)
  - Institute of Law (Box 37)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations (Box 37)
  - Institute of World Affairs (Box 37)
  - Institutes (misc.) (Box 37)
  - Inter-American (misc.) see also: Latin America (Box 37)
  - International Business Machines Corporation (Box 37)
  - International Business Machines Corporation (Box 38)
  - International Conference of American States (6th) (Box 38)
  - International Relations (Box 38)
  - International (misc.) (Box 38)
  - International Student Service Committee (Box 38)
  - Invitations, 1943-1945 (Box 38)
  - Invitations, 1946-1949 (Box 38)
  - Iowa (misc.) (Box 38)
  - Iowa, State University of (Box 38)
  - Irwin, Wallace (Box 38)
  - Irwin, Will (Box 38)
  - Jackson, J. Hugh (Box 39)
  - Jacqua, Ernest James (Box 39)
  - Jahncke, Ernest Lee ("Commodore") (Box 39)
  - James, Harlean (Box 39)
  - Japan & Japanese (Box 39)
  - Jefferson Memorial Foundation, Thomas (Box 39)
  - Jenkins, Olaf (Box 39)
  - Jenkins, Oliver Peebles (Box 39)
  - Jews (Box 39)
  - Johns Hopkins University (Box 39)
  - Johnson, Alvin Saunders (Box 39)
  - Johnson, Senator Hiram (Box 39)
  - Johnson, Nelsen Trusler (Assistant Secretary of State) (Box 39)
  - Johnston, Paul C. (Box 39)
  - Jones, Denton (Box 39)
  - Jones, Eliot (& Mrs.) (Box 39)
  - Jones, Herbert C. (Box 39)
  - Jordan, David Starr (Dr. &. Mrs.) (Box 39)
  - Jordan, Knight Starr (Box 39)
  - Joslin, Theodore G. (Box 39)
  - Judd, Lawrence M. (Governor of Hawaii) (Box 39)
  - Junior College (Box 39)
  - Junior Statesmen of America (Box 39)
  - Kahn, Julius H. (& Mrs. Florence P.) (Box 40)
  - Kaiser, Henry J. (Mr. & Mrs.) (Box 40)
  - Kansas (misc.) (Box 40)
  - Kansas, University of (Box 40)
  - Keating, John A. (son: Ralph, daughter: Hallie) (Box 40)
  - Keesling, Francis Valentine (Box 40)
  - Kefauver, Grayson Neikirk (Box 40)
  - Kelland, Clarence Budington ("Bud") (Box 40)
  - Kelley, Ernest J. (Box 40)
  - Kellogg, Frank d. (Box 40)
  - Kellogg, Frederick W. (Box 40)
  - Kellogg, W. K. (Arab Horse Ranch) (Box 40)
  - Kellogg, Vernon (Mrs. Charlotte Hoffman & daughter Jean K.) (Box 40)
  - Kendall, Lena (Mrs. Oscar J.) (Box 40)
  - Keppell, Dr. F. P. (Box 41)
  - Kessel, Mrs. Leo (Evelyn) (Box 41)
  - Keyes, Charles Henry (Box 41)
  - Kimball, Alice W. (Box 41)
  - Kimball, Dexter S. (Box 41)
  - Kimball, Mrs. May Dickenson (Box 41)
  - Kimball, Rufus H. (& Mrs. [Katherine Fairclugh]) (Box 41)
  - Kimber, Mrs. Arthur C. (Clara E.) & George C. K. (Box 41)
  - Kincade, Mrs. Forest J. (nee Elizabeth Peirce) (Box 41)
  - King, Marion (Box 41)
  - Kinley, David (Box 41)
  - Kiplinger Washington Letter (Box 41)
  - Kirkbride, Walter Harold (& Mrs.) (Box 41)
  - Kirtland, John Copeland (Box 41)
  - Kittredge, Frank A. (Box 41)
  - Kiwanis Club (Box 41)
  - Klein, Charles A. (Box 41)
  - vonKleinsmid, Rufus B (Box 41)
  - Kluegel, Mrs. Anne Jennings (Mrs. H. A.) (Box 41)
  - Kneass, Edward D. (Box 41)
  - Knoles, Tully C. (Box 41)
  - Knopf, Alfred A., Publishers (Box 41)
  - Kocel, Pierre (Box 41)
  - Kohlberg, Alfred E (Box 41)
  - Korea (Box 41)
  - Koster, Frederick J (Box 41)
  - Kotok, E. I. (Box 41)
  - Koverman, Mrs. Ida R. (Box 41)
  - Krauss, Frederick G. (Box 41)
  - Ku Klux Klan (Box 41)
  - LaBlanc, T. G. (Box 41)
  - Ladies Home Journal (Box 41)
  - Laird & Lee, Inc. (Box 41)
  - Lamont, Robert P. (& Mrs.) (Box 41)
  - Lamson, David (Box 41)
  - Landon, Alfred M. (Box 41)
  - Lane, Gertrude B. (Women's Home Company) (Box 41)
  - Lanz, Henry (& Mrs. Lisa L., #1) (Box 41)
  - Lanz, Henry (& Mrs. Lanz, #2) (Box 41)
  - Lapham, Roger Dearborn (Box 41)
  - Lasker, Bruno (Box 41)
  - Lathrop, Charles G. (Box 41)
  - Latin America, Committee on Cultural Relations with (Box 41)
  - Latin America, Relations with (misc.) (Box 41)
  - Lazarovich - Hrebelianovich, Princess Eleanor Calhoun (Box 41)
  - League of Nations (Box 42)
  - Leauge of Women Voters (see also: National League of women Voters) (Box 42)
  - Learned, Harry Barrett (Box 42)
  - Lee, Ivy L. (Box 42)
  - Legge, Alex (Box 42)
  - Legislation - Education (Box 42)
  - Legislation - Ham 'n Eggs (Box 42)
  - Legislation - misc. (Box 42)
  - Leib, Judge S. F. (Box 42)
  - Leither, Otho Clark (Box 42)
  - deLemos, Pedro J. (Box 42)
  - Lenox, Lionel Remond (Box 42)
  - Leonard, Mrs, Clare Ryan (John R.) (Box 42)
  - Lesley, Everett Parker (Mrs. & Jr.) (Box 42)
  - Leuschner, Armin Otto (Box 42)
  - Lewers, Charles R. (Box 42)
  - Lewis, James A. (Hoover Chauffeur) (Box 42)
  - Liang, Hubert S. (Box 42)
  - Liberal Arts Coll. Movement (promotion) (Box 42)
  - Liberal League, The (Box 42)
  - Life Magazine (Box 42)
  - Lillard, Jeremiah Beverley (Box 42)
  - Lillick, Ira Shell (Box 42)
  - Lincoln, Abraham (Box 42)
  - Lincoln Memorial University (Box 42)
  - Lindauer, Samson Arthur (Box 42)
  - Lippincott Company, J. B. (Box 43)
  - Literary Digest (Box 43)
  - Livermore, Norman B. (& Mrs. & Jr.) (Box 43)
  - Lving Age, The (Box 43)
  - Loofbourow, Leon L (Box 43)
  - Loomis, Francis B. (Box 43)
  - Los Angeles Times (Times Mirror Company) (Box 43)
  - Los Angeles - various organizations (Box 43)
  - Louisiana State University (Box 43)
  - Loew, Pardee (Box 43)
  - Lubin, Simon J. (Box 43)
  - Luce, Hrs. Clare Booth (Box 43)
  - Luce, Judge Edgar A. (Box 43)
  - Luce, Henry R. (Box 43)
  - Lucey, Capt. John F. (Box 43)
  - Lundborg, Louis B. (Box 43)
  - Lunn, Sir Henry S. (Box 43)
  - Lutz, Harley Leist (Box 43)
  - Lutz, Ralph Haswell (Box 43)
  - Lyman, John Carnahan (Box 43)
  - Lyon, A. R. (Box 43)
  - McBean, Atholl (&. Mrs.) (Box 44)
  - McClatchy, V. S. (Sacramento Bee) (Box 44)
  - McGormack, Edgar W. (Box 44)
  - McDaniel, Mrs. Laura Winans (Box 44)
  - McDonald, Mrs. Angus D. (Mary J.) (Box 44)
  - McDonald, Emanuel B ("Sam") (Box 44)
  - McDonnell, R. E. (Box 44)
  - McDowell, John Ezra (Box 44)
  - McGraw-Hill Publishing Company (Box 44)
  - McGregor, Richard C. (Box 44)
  - McGrew, John Tarn (Box 44)
  - McHose, John Cresco ("Nip") (Box 44)
  - Mack, Mrs. Reba G. (Box 44)
  - Mack, T. (Box 44)
  - Mackintosh, Kenneth (Box 44)
  - McLaine, William L. (Box 44)
  - McLaughlin, Mrs. Alfred (Emma M.) (Box 44)
  - MacLean, Mrs. Charles A., Jr. (Hulda Hoover) (Box 44)
  - MacLennan, Mrs. Russell Malcolm (Catherine ) (Box 44)
  - Macklin, Theodore (Box 44)
  - MacMillan Company (Box 44)
  - McMullin, Mrs. Dare Stark (Box 44)
  - McNab, John L. (Box 44)
  - McNemar, Capt. Leslie C. (Box 44)
  - MacQuarrie, Thomas William (Box 44)
  - MacWhite, Michael (Box 44)
  - deMadariaga, Salvador (Box 44)
  - Malone, Ted (Box 44)
  - Malone, George W. (Box 44)
  - Mandel, William (Box 44)
  - Manuscripts (Wilbur, Ray Lyman), 1916-1924 (Box 45)
  - Manuscripts (Wilbur, Ray Lyman), 1925-1927 (Box 45)
  - Manuscripts (Wilbur, Ray Lyman), 1928-1931 (Box 45)
  - Manuscripts (Wilbur, Ray Lyman), 1932-1935 (Box 46)
  - Manuscripts (Wilbur, Ray Lyman), 1936-1937 (Box 46)
  - Manuscripts (Wilbur, Ray Lyman), 1938 (Box 47)
  - Manuscripts (Wilbur, Ray Lyman), 1939 (Box 47)
  - Manuscripts (Wilbur, Ray Lyman), 1940 (Box 47)
  - Manuscripts (Wilbur, Ray Lyman), 1941 (Box 48)
  - Manuscripts (Wilbur, Ray Lyman), 1942 (Box 48)
  - Manuscripts (Wilbur, Ray Lyman), 1943 (Box 48)
  - Manuscripts (Wilbur, Ray Lyman), 1944-1945 (Box 48)
  - Manuscripts (Wilbur, Ray Lyman), 1946-1949 (Box 49)
  - Mark Twain Society (also, Mark Twain Centennial Committee, etc.) (Box 49)
  - Martin, Charles Emannuel (Box 49)
  - Marvin, Cloyd H. (Box 49)
  - Marx, Charles David (Box 49)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Box 49)
  - Massey, Vincent (Box 49)
  - Masson, Adele (Box 49)
  - Masters, Alfred R. (Box 49)
  - Mayer, Louis B. (Box 49)
  - Mayer, Mr. & Mrs Max (Julia B.) (Box 49)
  - Mayflower Hotel (Box 49)
  - Mears, Mrs. David O. (Mary Grinnell) (Box 49)
  - Mears, Elliot Grinnell (Prof.) (Box 49)
  - Meiklejohn, Alexander (Box 49)
  - Mellon, Andrew W. (Box 49)
  - Meloney, Mrs. William Brown (Marie Mattingly Brown) (Box 49)
  - Menlo School & College (Box 49)
  - Merriam, John C. (Box 49)
  - Branner, John Casper (out of place) (Box 49)
  - Merrill, Charles Washington (Box 49)
  - Merritt, Ralph P. (Box 49)
  - Metcalf, John B. (Box 49)
  - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company (Box 49)
  - Mexican Treaty, Congressional Record re (Box 49)
  - Mexico (Box 49)
  - Meyer, Eugene & Mrs. (Agnes E.) (Box 49)
  - Meyreis, L. J. (Box 49)
  - Michigan, University of (Box 49)
  - Mickey, Mrs. Amanda (Box 49)
  - Mierow, Charles Christopher (Box 50)
  - Milbank, Mr. & Mrs. Jerry (& Kitty) (Box 50)
  - Miles, Walter R. (& Mrs.) (Box 50)
  - Miller, Bernice (Box 50)
  - Miller, Christian Otto Gerberding (Box 50)
  - Miller, Clifton M. (Box 50)
  - Miller, Guy C. (Box 50)
  - Miller, Mr. and Mrs. Frank A. (Box 50)
  - Miller, Mrs. Henry C. (Dorothy Carr) (Box 50)
  - Miller, Justin (Box 50)
  - Miller, Mrs. Walter McNab (Helen Richards) (Box 50)
  - Millikan, Robert Andrews (Box 50)
  - Mills College (Box 50)
  - Mills, Ogden Livingston (Box 50)
  - Minnesota, University of (Box 50)
  - Mirrleslees, Edith Ronald (Box 50)
  - Mitchell, Frances F. (Sgt.) (Box 50)
  - Mitchell, J. Pearce (Box 50)
  - Mitchell, Mrs. Lydia P. (John W.) (Box 50)
  - Mitchell, William deWitt (Attorney General) (Box 50)
  - Montana, University of (Box 50)
  - Monteagle, Paige (Box 50)
  - Montezuma School (Box 50)
  - Mooney, James Elliott (Box 50)
  - Moore, Ethel (Box 50)
  - Moore, Harry H. (Box 50)
  - Moore, Mr. & Mrs. Robert S. (Florence) (Box 50)
  - Moral Re-armament (Box 50)
  - Morell, George F. (Box 50)
  - Morgan, Percy T. (Box 50)
  - Morrison, Frank W (Box 51)
  - Morton, Mr. and Mrs. Oliver Perry (Box 51)
  - Motion Pictures, etc. (Box 51)
  - Motion Pictures Research Council, 1934-1935 (Box 51)
  - Motion Pictures Research Council, 1938 (Box 52)
  - Motion Pictures Research Council, 1939 (Box 52)
  - Motion Pictures Research Council, 1940-1941 (Box 53)
  - Motion Pictures Research Council, 1942, 1949 (Box 53)
  - Moynihan, Charles J. (Box 53)
  - Mullgardt, Louis Christian (Box 53)
  - Mumford, Lewis (Box 53)
  - Munro, William Bennett (Box 53)
  - Murray, Augustus Taber (Prof.) (Box 53)
  - Myers, George Sprague (Box 53)
  - Mysels, Mrs. Karol J. (Helen) (Box 53)
  - Nation, The (Box 53)
  - National (various organizations A-Z) (Box 53)
  - National Academy of American Literature (Box 54)
  - National Audubon Society (Box 54)
  - National Child Labor Committee (Box 54)
  - National Civic Federation (Box 54)
  - National Committee for Art Appreciation (Box 54)
  - National Committee on Education (World Congress) (Box 54)
  - National Conference on Family Life (Box 54)
  - National Conference on Social Work (Box 54)
  - National Conference on Outdoor Recreation (Box 54)
  - National Conference on State Parks (Box 54)
  - National Congress of Parents & Teachers (Box 54)
  - National Council against Conscription (see also, conscription, peace time compulsory) (Box 54)
  - National Council for Prevention of War (Box 54)
  - National Council for Protection Roadside Beauty (Box 54)
  - National Economic League (Box 54)
  - National Education Association of the United States (Box 54)
  - National Forest Preservation Commission (Box 54)
  - National Go to Church Campaign (Box 55)
  - National Institute of Social Sciences (Box 55)
  - National Institution of Public Affairs (Box 55)
  - National League of Women Voters (Box 55)
  - National Parks Association (Box 55)
  - National Policy Committee (Box 55)
  - National Press Clubs (Box 55)
  - National Recovery Administration (NRA) (Box 55)
  - National Research Council (Box 55)
  - National Resources Committee (Box 55)
  - National Safety Council (Box 55)
  - National Security Committee (Box 55)
  - National Security League (Box 55)
  - National Student Federation of America (Box 55)
  - National University in Washington (Box 55)
  - Nation's Business, The (Box 55)
  - Nealley, Willie Grafton (Box 55)
  - Near East Relief (Box 55)
  - Nebraska, University of (Box 55)
  - Negroes (Box 55)
  - Neidig, William Jonathan (Box 56)
  - Neihardt, John G. (Box 56)
  - Nevada, University of (Box 56)
  - Newcomen Society of England (Box 56)
  - New England Historical Genealogical Society (Box 56)
  - Newhall, William May (Box 56)
  - New Mexico, University of (Box 56)
  - New Republic, The (Box 56)
  - Newsom, John F. (Box 56)
  - Newsweek (Box 56)
  - Newton, Walter H. (Box 56)
  - New York (misc.) (Box 56)
  - New York College of the City of (Box 56)
  - New York Herald Tribune (Box 56)
  - New York Times (Box 56)
  - New York University (Box 56)
  - New York University of the State of (Box 56)
  - New York World (Box 56)
  - New York World's Fair (Box 56)
  - Neylan, John Francis (Box 56)
  - Nichols, John Ralph (Box 56)
  - Nichols, Walter Hammond (Box 56)
  - Nichols, William Ford (Bishop) (Box 56)
  - Nickel, J. Leroy (Box 56)
  - Nobel Peace Prize (Box 56)
  - Noble, Mrs. Myrtle L. (Box 56)
  - North American Newspaper Alliance (Box 56)
  - North, Arthur W. (Box 56)
  - North Carolina, University of (Box 56)
  - Northwestern University (Box 56)
  - Nourse, John T. (Box 56)
  - Nyack Plan (Box 56)
  - Oakland, various organizations of (Box 56)
  - Oakland - Education, public schools, etc. (Box 56)
  - Oakland Forum (Box 56)
  - Oddie Hon. Tasker L. (see Hiram Johnson, W. J. Donovan, Harry Chandler re Hoover Dam) (Box 56)
  - Odum, Howard Washington (Box 56)
  - Ohio State University (Box 56)
  - Oil (Box 56)
  - Olney, Warren, Jr. (Box 56)
  - Open Road, Inc. (& International Student Hospitality Association) (Box 56)
  - Oregon Trail Memorial Association (Box 56)
  - Oregon, University of (& Oregon State System of Higher Education) (Box 56)
  - Oregonian, The (Box 57)
  - Oriental Survey Exclusion Relations (Box 57)
  - Oskinson, John Milton (Box 57)
  - Pacific Ocean School (Box 57)
  - Pacific School of Religion (Box 57)
  - Pacific Spectator, The (Box 57)
  - Pacific Union Club (Box 57)
  - Paderewski, Ignace (& Paderewski Fund for Polish Relief) (Box 57)
  - Paist, Mr. & Mrs. Frederick M. (Box 57)
  - Palmer, Frederick (Box 57)
  - Palo Alto - Board of Education, Chamber of Commerce (Box 57)
  - Palo Alto Times & Peninsula Newspapers (Box 57)
  - Pan American (misc.) (Box 57)
  - Pan American Reciprocal Trade Conference (Box 57)
  - Pan American Trade Committee (Box 57)
  - Pan American Union (Box 58)
  - Parker, Mrs. Agnew McCall (Box 58)
  - Parkin, William Metcalf (Box 58)
  - Parr, Fred D. (Box 58)
  - Parsons, Edward Lambe (Bishop) (Box 58)
  - Pasadena (various organizations) (Box 58)
  - Pass In Review (Box 58)
  - Pathfinders of America (Box 58)
  - Peace (misc.) (Box 58)
  - Pearl Harbor (Box 58)
  - Pearson, Drew (Box 58)
  - Pearson, Lucy Helen (Box 58)
  - Pease, Mrs. Vera Jane Wheeler Edwards #1 (Box 58)
  - Pease, Mrs. Vera Jane Wheeler Edwards #2 (Box 59)
  - Pease, Mrs. Vera Jane Wheeler Edwards #3 (Box 59)
  - Peirce, George James (Box 59)
  - Peninsula Volunteers (Box 59)
  - Pennsylvania, University of (Box 59)
  - Peoples Legislative Service (Box 59)
  - Perry, Mr. & Mrs. David Rouse (Mrs. Lilly Charles McFadden-Perry) (Box 59)
  - Pershing, John J. (Box 59)
  - Peterson, Harry G (Box 59)
  - Petree, Neil H. (Box 59)
  - Pettus, William Bacon (Box 59)
  - Phelan, James D. (Box 59)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 59)
  - Philharmonic Society of San Mateo County (Box 59)
  - Philippines, The (Box 59)
  - Phleger, Herman (Box 59)
  - Photo Scribe Associates (Box 59)
  - Pickens, Mr. and Mrs. Robert Sylvester (Box 59)
  - Pickering, LeRoy (Box 59)
  - Pierce, Lyman L. (Pierce &. Hedrick) (Box 59)
  - Poems & Poetry (misc.) (Box 59)
  - Point Lobos (& Save the Redwoods League) (Box 60)
  - Poling, Daniel A. (Box 60)
  - Politics (Box 60)
  - Pollack, Jack H. (Box 60)
  - Pollard, Mrs. Joseph G. (Alice) (Box 60)
  - Pope, Arthur Upham (Box 60)
  - Popper, Herbert Jan (Box 60)
  - Post War Economic Planning Committee (for full employment & free enterprise) (Box 60)
  - Post War World Council (Box 60)
  - Powell Company, L. D. (Powell Publishing Company) (Box 60)
  - Powell, Walter (Box 60)
  - Power, Ralph L. (Box 60)
  - Prado, Miguel Angel (Box 60)
  - Pratt, Sir John (Box 60)
  - Price, Ernest B. (Box 60)
  - Price, Francis (Box 60)
  - Price, George Clinton (Box 60)
  - Price, William Wightman (Box 60)
  - Princeton University (Box 60)
  - Proctor, A. Phimister (Box 60)
  - Prison Industries Reorganization Administration (Box 60)
  - Prohibition (Box 60)
  - Pritchett, Henry Smith (Box 60)
  - Progressive Education Association (Box 60)
  - Public Relations Institute of the West (Box 60)
  - Puerto Rico (Box 60)
  - Pugh, Edmund Wright (& Jr.) (Box 60)
  - Purdue University (Box 60)
  - Putnam, Mr. & Mrs. Edward Kirby (Box 60)
  - Queen, Hallie Elver (Box 60)
  - Race Relations (Box 61)
  - Radio (misc.) (Box 61)
  - Radio - Columbia Broadcasting System (Box 61)
  - Radio - National Advisory Council on Radio in Education (Box 61)
  - Radio - National Committee on Education by (Box 61)
  - Radio - National Broadcasting Company (Box 61)